Laszlo Somogyi

Phone: +44 771188 9483 | Email: laszlo.somogyi@protonmail.com LinkedIn: /in/laszlo-somogyi/ | GitHub: /laszlosomogyimusic/ Portfolio: https://laszlosomogyimusic.com/

SUMMARY

Front end web developer with creative skills and strong analytical knowledge. 10 years of consulting experience, to help customers gather business requirements and deliver projects accordingly. 18 years of Avaya contact centre field engineering knowledge, designed, delivered, and installed self-service projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical Languages: React.js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, Document Object Model, BootStrap, jQuery, Moment.js, Java, SQL

Applications: Shopify, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, MS SQL Server, Avaya Orchestration Designer, Avaya Communication Manager, Twilio, Amazon Connect, Nuance Text To Speech, Nuance Speech Recognition

PROJECTS

Click Studio https://github.com/milla56/Click-Studio https://milla56.github.io/Click-Studio/

- First group project of the Skills Bootcamp. We designed and developed a website which using Shutterstock image and video search API calls
- Responsible for the JavaScript programming, jQuery DOM manipulation and API calls
- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Laszlo Somogyi Music

02/2023 – Redditch, UK

- Supported a client to create a Shopify business. https://www.ourcraftnook.com
- Experience in developing the front end of a website based on the design requirements

Applications Consultant Maintel

07/2018 - 02/2023 Birmingham, UK

- Completed pre-sales tasks, provided technical details for sales.
- Wrote High Level Design for business and Low Level Design with technical details
- Designed and developed a multilingual, database driven dynamic self-service project for a mobile provider with a lot of RESTful API integration.
- Delivered a multilingual self-service project for a large European customer. Designed and developed non-factory text to speech grammars for Eastern European and North European languages.
- Designed and developed a self-service application for a customer in the UK public sector using SMS and web chat APIs.

Technical Consultant Cyara

11/2016 – 06/2018 Birmingham, UK

- Collaborated closely with the sales, pre-sales and marketing team.
- Assisted customers to design test scenarios using Cyara products.
- Collected test results, analysed data, and provided detailed feedback to the customer.
- Delivered an automated, multichannel contact centre monitoring framework for a mobile provider.
- Delivered training for a large bank's testing department including managers and executives.

 Consultant
 08/2012 – 10/2016

 Geomant UK
 Alcester, UK

- Completed pre-sales tasks, provided technical details for sales.
- Wrote High Level Design for business and Low Level Design with technical details
- Lead Avaya self-service deployment and development projects with a small team.
- Transitioned a City Council's old contact centre to Avaya platform.
- Designed and developed a complex multilingual self-service application using speech recognition and text to speech.

Senior System Engineer Geomant Hungary

04/2004 – 05/2012 Budapest, Hungary

- Wrote Low Level Design with technical details.
- Delivered Avaya training for colleagues and customers.
- Designed and developed a full database driven self-service IVR project.
- Developed text to speech grammars for Eastern European customers.

Web Developer Pixelpark Hungary

09/2000 – 12/2003

Budapest, Hungary

- Developing web applications.
- Travelled to the UK and Austria to be part of an international developer team.
- Developed a horizontal web portal for a large UK customer.
- Did various web projects for Austrian customers.

Software Developer Prompt 92 Hungary

09/1998 - 08/2000 Budapest, Hungary

- Developed Windows based multimedia applications
- Travelled to Germany to a customer site

EDUCATION

Certificate, Skills Bootcamp in Front-end Web Development & UX: University of Birmingham A 16-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, BootStrap, DOM, Node.js, React.js, Moment.js